Derek Taylor

Dktaylor916@gmail.com

+44 7724 113 738

London, UK 🍫



Portfolio

I am a full-stack GIS developer and data visualization specialist with over eight years of professional experience. I excel at transforming complex data into clear, actionable insights and communicating results to both technical and non-technical audiences. My work involves cleaning/maintaining large datasets, building backend data pipelines/API's, and developing compelling frontend interactive visualizations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Spatial Design Hub (Spatial Design Hub)

Aug. 2023 - Present

GIS Developer

London, UK

- As a GIS Developer for the GIS Consultancy Spatial Design Hub my roles include:
 - o Lead developer for the web application/dashboard Rail Insights (frontend and backend) designed to visualize complex rail modeling results for Network Rail in the UK
 - Lead developer for the web application Urban Access (frontend and backend) designed to assist transport planners with data analysis and site planning
 - Cleaning and maintaining data pipelines/API's using pandas and MongoDB
 - Coding and creating interactive maps using MapBoxGL and Javascript (Svelte) with various functionalities and animations to enhance the visual storytelling

The Pudding (The Pudding)

Aug. 2023

Freelance Data Journalist

London, UK

- Selected as a freelance journalist for the online publication The Pudding to code, write, and produce a visual story on Climate Zones:
 - o Worked collaboratively with staff members of The Pudding to storyboard and workshop ideas
 - Project is designed in Figma, coded in Svelte

Beyond Words Studio (Beyond Words)

Oct. 2022 - Aug. 2023

Freelance Data Visualization and GIS Specialist

London, UK

- As a data analyst for the data journalism and design firm Beyond Words Studio my roles include:
 - Collecting, cleaning, analyzing data to design physical map visualizations, including a Covid map presented at an installation for the Bill Gates Foundation
 - Building a 3D elevation model of Africa using open source satellite data, Rasterio, and Blender. Combining the model with farming system data in QGIS to give an insight to the relationship of climate and elevation on farming systems in the continent

Goudappel (Goudappel)

June 2018 - June 2022

Data Scientist and GIS Specialist / US Policy Researcher

Amsterdam, Netherlands

- As a data scientist for the Dutch transportation firm Goudappel I was responsible for:
 - Collecting, cleaning, analyzing, and visualizing real-world data from Dutch and international municipalities (including Amsterdam, San Francisco, and Gothenburg) using advanced python, SQL, and GIS techniques to present social, transportation, and environmental data (ex. Allocation of Public Space in the Netherlands)
 - Transforming technical and complex data outputs from transportation models into interactive and visually stimulating visualizations to better inform stakeholders in the planning process (ex. Data Mapping Examples)

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

Dec. 2017

Bachelor of Science: City Planning, Geospatial Information Systems and Technology

Berkeley, California

- GPA 3.85, College of Natural Resources High Distinction
- Studied urban design in Copenhagen, Denmark during spring 2016 semester (Copenhagen University)

CERTIFICATIONS, SKILLS, LANGUAGES & INTERESTS

- Certifications: CS50x: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science (HarvardX), Algorithms Specialization (Stanford Online)
- Skills: Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, Svelte, D3.js, QGIS, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, GitHub, scikit-learn, TensorFlow
- Languages: English (Native Language), French (B2), Dutch (B2)
- Interests: Biking, surfing, playing drums, saunas, chess, jumping into cold bodies of water